This is Everyday Grammar. I'm John Russell. Adverbs can be a difficult topic for some.
If you mention the word to many native English speakers, you might get this kind of reaction.
Do not fear. Adverbs are not as scary as some might think.
For today's lesson, we will talk about just one use of adverbs to modify verbs.
When adverbs are modifying verbs, they often answer a how question.
What is a how question?
Here's an example.
Recently, I was visiting a new city.
I asked a man for directions.
When he spoke his words came too quickly for me to understand I said wow he speaks quickly
In the sentence, he speaks quickly, speak is the verb, and quickly is the adverb.
Quickly described speak.
In other words, quickly answers the how question.
How does this person speak?
He speaks quickly.
Let's take another example.
Imagine you are watching a turtle move.
How does the turtle move?
Slowly.
So you could say, the turtle moves slowly.
There are many other uses of adverbs, but for today, just remember that adverbs often
have an ly ending and often modify a verb. And that's Everyday Grammar.